Finding Aid for West Side United Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.) Records, 1846-2000
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
West Side United Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records 1846-2000 1950-1999
West Side United Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
06100 Ba 2
Church originally established by German immigrant families to Ann Arbor, Michigan. Quarterly and annual reports of the church, records of church boards and commissions, Sunday School minutes and reports, subject files, publications, visual materials, and sound recordings.
16 linear feet in 17 boxes
12.7 GB online
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was transferred from the West Side United Methodist Church (Donor No. 3229 ) in December 1999.
The record group is open to research.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
German immigrant families founded the Erste Deutsche Methodisten Kirche in 1847 and built a church at the corner of East Liberty and South Division. Over the next half century the congregation gradually outgrew this building, so in 1895 they purchased a new site in the heart of the German section of Ann Arbor, now known as the Old West Side. The new church, completed in 1896, was located at the corner of West Jefferson and Fourth Streets.
For many years, the church membership continued to be drawn from the German families of Ann Arbor, but over time, the church began holding both German-language services and English services. Like most German-American institutions, the church came under suspicion of disloyalty during and just after World War I. In 1919, the church was forced to close for a few months. Upon reopening, the congregation gave up German language services and changed its name to West Side Methodist Episcopal Church.
The church did not grow significantly in size until just after World War II. Soon after the arrival of Rev. Edwin Weiss in 1948, membership began surging, almost doubling in the next three years. The congregation outgrew its old church and in 1950 purchased a site on South Seventh Street to build a new one. They moved into the new church in 1952.
In 1955, the congregation purchased a small home to the north of the church to expand its site. Two years later they began a fund raising campaign to eliminate the balance owed on the church building and provide money to build an education building. This campaign was so successful that they not only completed the education building, but also added a Moeller Pipe Organ and purchased a small piece of land south of the sanctuary for the addition of a driveway.
Over the following fifteen years, the church made significant additions to the pipe organ, installed the stained glass windows, paved the driveways and parking lot, and added additional land north of the education building. In 1988, the congregation completed a renovation of the education building and the construction of a connecting wing between it and the church.
The West Side United Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.) record group contains all extant records of the West Side United Methodist Church of Ann Arbor from its founding as the Erste Deutsche Methodisten Kirche in 1847 up to the 1990s. All records dating prior to World War I are in German, those from later time periods are in English.
Records from the German period are not complete, but do include quarterly conference meeting minutes (1847-1867 and 1883-1916), official board minutes (1897-1908), Sunday School board meeting minutes (1876-1915), Sunday School attendance and contribution records (1901-1918), a record of baptisms (1857-1901), minutes of meetings of the leaders (1901-1908), Epworth League minutes (1900-1917), and records on receipts and expenditures (1879-1893).
Records from the years since World War I vary in completeness depending on the time period. Records from the years prior to the move to the church on Seventh Street in 1952 are less complete than those for the most recent decades. For the period from World War I to 1952, the collection contains quarterly conference reports for most years; official board minutes (1922-1931 and 1944-1952); Board of Christian Education minutes and correspondence (1943-1952); Ladies Aid/Women's Society for Christian Service records (1935-1952); Sunday School board minutes and records on attendance, contributions, and expenditures (1923-1952 - incomplete); letters from former pastors and their wives upon celebrating the 40th anniversary of the Jefferson Street church (1934); photographs of the church building and activities of the congregation, yearbooks (1946-1952), and correspondence concerning the sale of the Jefferson Street church and the construction of the Seventh Street church (1949-1952).
The records for the years since 1952 are relatively complete and quite extensive. Included are quarterly (more recently annual) conference reports, minutes and correspondence of major boards and commissions (Administrative Council, Board of Trustees, Education, Evangelism, Finance, Memorials, Council on Ministries, Missions, Nominations, Outreach, Staff-Parish Relations, United Methodist Women, and Worship) plus various short-lived temporary committees and task forces, correspondence chronological files, subject files on special projects and events, church newsletters, Sunday bulletins, directories, and photographs of the church building and activities of the congregation.
The record group is arranged in six series: Quarterly and Annual Reports, Boards and Commissions File, Sunday School File, Topical File, Publications File, Photographs File, and Audiotapes, Films and Video.
Researchers interested in baptismal and marriage records should contact West Side United Methodist Church.
Subjects:
West Side United Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Church history.; German Americans--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Church buildings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; United Methodist Church (U.S.)--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
West Side United Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Churches.; United Methodist Church (U.S.)--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
West Side United Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Quarterly and Annual Reports
  The Quarterly and Annual Reports series (1.5 feet) dates from the founding of the church in 1847 and is relatively complete with the exception of a gap from 1868-1882 and a few years during the 1920s. The early records are contained in bound volume. The person designated as secretary of the quarterly church conference recorded the minutes in these books in German, including reports on church and Sunday School activities and finances. The records began to be recorded in English during World War I, but the format also changed. Instead of recording minutes and reports in bound volumes, the officers began filling out pre-printed forms that could easily be submitted to various officials. In addition to minutes of the conference, separate reports from the minister, treasurer, trustees, Sunday School superintendent, Epworth League (later the Youth Fellowship) president, president of the Ladies' Aid Society (later the Women's Society for Christian Service), etc. Over the years, these reports became more and more detailed, especially for the Fourth Quarterly Conference. In 1969, the church shifted from quarterly conferences to a single annual conference. The files continue to contain minutes of the meetings plus detailed reports of various church officials to the Detroit Conference.
  - Annual Conference and Reports 1969-2000, 23 folders (Box 1)
  - Quarterly Conference Reports
    - 1847-1867 (Box 1)
      (in German with typed translations of some meetings)
    - 1883-1916, 3 volumes (Box 1)
      (in German)
    - 1917-1919 (Box 1)
    - 1923-1928, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1929-1968, 19 folders (Box 2)
- Boards and Commissions File
  The Boards and Commissions File (5.6 feet) contains records of church bodies organized to help run various aspects of the work of the church. The structure of the church has evolved over time, becoming more and more complex. The earliest records in this series date from the late 19th and early 20th century and document the work of the Official Board, a predecessor of the Administrative Board (later known as the Administrative Council and now known as the Church Council). In general, however, this series contains little dating from the early history of the church, focusing instead on the past forty to fifty years. Included in the files are minutes, reports, and correspondence. Major boards and commissions documented, in addition to the Administrative Council, are the Board of Trustees (starting in 1957), Education (starting in 1943), Evangelism (starting in 1963), Every Member Commitment (starting in 1980), Finance (starting in 1953), Memorials (starting in 1971), Council on Ministries (1969-1982), Missions (1962-1982), Outreach (starting 1982), Staff-Parish Relations (starting 1976), United Methodist Women and its predecessors (starting 1926), and Worship (starting 1965). In addition the series contains information on temporary committees and task forces set up to study specific problems or engage in long-range planning.
  - Administrative Council
    (formerly the Official Board and Administrative Board)
    - General 1953-1996, 7 folders (Box 2)
    - Minutes
      - 1897-1908 (Box 2)
      - 1922-1931 (Box 2)
      - 1931-1944, 1 volumes (Box 2)
      - 1944-1955, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - 1956-1963, 4 folders (Box 3)
      - 1965-1995, 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Board of Trustees
    - General
      - 1955-1956 (Box 3)
      - 1964-1996, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - Minutes
      - 1957-1972 (incomplete) (Box 3)
      - 1975-1996, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Building Committee 1957-1959 (Box 3)
    (re construction of education building)
  - Bus Committee 1972-1991 (Box 3)
  - Capital Improvements Funding Committee 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Day Care Committee 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Education Building Use Task Force 1984 (Box 3)
  - Education Commission
    (formerly Board of Christian Education-See also Sunday School Series)
    - Financial Reports 1953-1957 (Box 3)
    - General 1943-1964, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - General
      - 1965-1967, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - 1969-1996, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Minutes
      - 1943-1967, 5 folders (Box 4)
      - 1969-1996, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Evangelism, Commission on
    - General 1953-1996, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Minutes
      - 1963-1967 (Box 4)
      - 1977-1983 (Box 4)
      - 1986-1996, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Every Member Commitment Committee
    - 1980-1985 (Box 4)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 4)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    - 1990 (Box 4)
    - 1991-1993 (Box 4)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 4)
  - Finance, Committee on
    - Budget Proposals
      - 1950-1965 (Box 4)
      - 1966-1978 (Box 4)
      - 1979-1997 (Box 4)
    - Financial Reports
      - 1953-1956 (Box 4)
      - 1957-1959 (Box 4)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 4)
      - 1964-1966 (Box 4)
      - 1967-1970 (Box 5)
      - 1971-1974 (Box 5)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 5)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 5)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 5)
      - 1981-1983 (Box 5)
      - 1984-1986 (Box 5)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 5)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 5)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 5)
      - 1993-1994 (Box 5)
      - 1995 (Box 5)
      - 1996 (Box 5)
    - General
      - 1953-1955 (Box 5)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 5)
      - 1958 (Box 5)
      - 1959-1961 (Box 5)
      - 1962-1965 (Box 5)
      - 1966-1968 (Box 5)
      - 1969-1971 (Box 5)
      - 1972-1976 (Box 5)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 5)
      - 1979-1989 (Box 5)
      - 1990-1996 (Box 5)
    - Minutes
      - 1954-1955 (Box 5)
      - 1962-1966 (Box 5)
      - 1967-1970 (Box 5)
      - 1971-1976 (Box 5)
      - 1977-1981 (Box 5)
      - 1982-1986 (Box 5)
      - 1987-1991 (Box 5)
      - 1992-1995 (Box 5)
  - Football Parking Committee 1990-1996 (Box 5)
  - Long-Range Planning Committee
    - Undated 1979 (Box 5)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 5)
    - 1984-1988 (Box 5)
  - Memorials Committee
    - Baylis Fund 1970-1977 (Box 6)
    - General
      - 1971-1977 (Box 6)
      - 1978-1982 (Box 6)
      - 1983-1988 (Box 6)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 6)
      - 1991-1994 (Box 6)
      - 1995-1996 (Box 6)
    - Minutes
      - 1976-1988 (Box 6)
      - 1989-1996 (Box 6)
    - Notebooks, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Ministries, Council on
    - General 1969-1982 (Box 6)
    - Minutes and Correspondence
      - 1969-1976 (Box 6)
      - 1965-1968 (Box 6)
  - Missions, Commission on
    - General 1962-1983 (Box 6)
    - Minutes
      - 1962-1966 (Box 6)
      - 1967-1982 (Box 6)
  - Nominations, Committee on
    - General
      - 1965-1984 (Box 6)
      - 1985-1991 (Box 6)
      - 1992-1994 (Box 6)
      - 1994-1996 (Box 6)
    - Notebook 1992-1994 (Box 6)
  - Organ Renovation Task Force 1989-1996 (Box 6)
  - Outreach Commission
    - General 1982-1996 (Box 6)
    - Minutes 1984-1996 (Box 6)
  - Parsonage Study Committee 1990-1996 (Box 6)
  - Policy Planning Committee 1965 (Box 6)
  - Social Concerns Commission 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Staff-Parish Relations Committee
    (formerly Pastor-Parish Relations Committee)
    - General
      - 1956 1979-1986 (Box 6)
      - 1987-1989 (Box 6)
      - 1990 (Box 6)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - 1993 (Box 6)
      - 1994 (Box 7)
      - 1995 (Box 7)
    - Job Descriptions (Box 7)
    - Local Church Profiles 1987-1989 (Box 7)
    - Minutes
      - 1976-1978 (Box 7)
      - 1981-1984 (Box 7)
      - 1985-1989 (Box 7)
      - 1990-1993 (Box 7)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - United Methodist Men 1988-1991 (Box 7)
  - United Methodist Women
    (formerly Ladies Aid/Women's Society of Christian Service)
    - Annual Reports 1926-1956 (Box 7)
    - Directories
      - 1979-1985 (Box 7)
      - 1986-1989 (Box 7)
      - 1990-1994 (Box 7)
    - Executive Board Minutes
      - 1940-1943 (Box 7)
      - 1944-1949 (Box 7)
      - 1949-1953 (Box 7)
    - General
      - Undated (Box 7)
      - 1942-1994 (Box 7)
    - History Covering 1935-1961 by Betty Reynolds (Box 7)
    - Minutes 1989-1994 (Box 7)
    - Record and Report Book
      - 1946 (Box 7)
      - 1947 (Box 7)
      - 1948-1949 (Box 7)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 7)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 7)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 7)
      - 1952-1953 (Box 7)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 7)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 7)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 7)
    - Remittance of Pledges to Missions 1973-1976 (Box 7)
  - Worship Commission
    - General
      - 1972-1990 (Box 7)
      - 1991-1996 (Box 7)
    - Minutes
      - 1965 1973-1984 (Box 8)
      - 1985-1990 (Box 8)
      - 1991-1996 (Box 8)
  - Worship Task Group 1989-1993 (Box 8)
  - Youth Committee 1958 (Box 8)
- Sunday School File
  For the most part, the Sunday School File (0.8 feet) concerns the period from 1876 to 1952. Included are Board minutes and reports on attendance and contributions.
  - Attendance
    - Attendance Books
      - 1930s undated or 1940s undated (Box 8)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 8)
    - Attendance and Contribution Records
      - 1901-1907 (Box 8)
      - 1907-1913 (Box 8)
      - 1913-1918 (Box 8)
      - 1919-1922 (Box 8)
      - 1922-1923 (Box 8)
      - 1924-1925 (Box 8)
      - 1925-1932 (Box 8)
        (includes board meeting minutes, 1925-26)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 8)
      - 1949-1952 (Box 8)
  - Board Meeting Minutes
    (see also Education Commission in Boards and Commissions)
    - 1876-1897 (Box 8)
    - 1897-1907 (Box 8)
    - 1907-1918 (Box 8)
      (mostly in German)
    - 1927-1931 (Box 8)
  - Expenditures 1927-1931 (Box 8)
  - Student Names and Addresses
    - 1923 (Box 8)
    - 1924 (Box 8)
- Topical File
  The Topical File (1.9 feet) contains a variety of materials from all time periods. A baptism record book, minutes of church leaders, and a record of receipts and expenditures date from the German-language era of the church. A small amount of material concerns the Jefferson Street building. The bulk of the file dates from the more recent history of the church. Included is correspondence concerning the sale of the Jefferson Street building, the construction of the new church on Seventh Street, and improvements to the Seventh Street building (including the construction of the education building and the connecting wing). Other materials include the minister's correspondence file for some scattered years, information about the stained glass windows, notes and presentations on the history of the church, information on anniversary celebrations, minutes of two of the women's' circles, and records on youth activities, including the Epworth League and the United Methodist Youth Fellowship.
  - Anniversaries
    - 110th 1956 (Box 8)
    - 125th 1971 (Box 8)
    - 140th 1987 (Box 8)
    - 150th 1997, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Articles of Incorporation 1848-1990 (Box 9)
  - Attendance Statistics 1958-1968 (Box 9)
  - Baker, Dianne-Musical Compositions 1983-1987 (Box 9)
  - Baptism Record Book 1857-1901 (Box 9)
  - Building Fund Drive 1990-1998 (Box 9)
  - Cherub Choir 1958-1960 (Box 9)
  - Choir 1954, 1957, 1974-1978 (Box 9)
  - Christian Education at West Side-Article by Tillie Bauer (Box 9)
  - Christian Education Endowment Fund 1991-1994 (Box 9)
  - Church Building Renovation and Expansion 1986-1988, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Church Relocation from Jefferson Street to Seventh Street
    - 1949 (Box 9)
    - 1950 (Box 9)
    - 1951 (Box 9)
    - 1952 (Box 9)
  - Clergy Seats and Balcony Pews Purchase 1953-1955 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence Chronological
    - General (Box 9)
    - 1957 (Box 9)
    - 1958 (Box 9)
    - 1959 (Box 9)
    - 1960 (Box 9)
    - 1973 (Box 9)
    - 1974 (Box 9)
    - 1975 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence-Minister's Letters to the Congregation 1953-1957 (Box 9)
  - Dorcas Circle Minutes 1982-1985 (Box 9)
  - Education Building Specifications 1958 (Box 9)
  - Interfaith Hospitality Network Homeless Shelter Program 1992-1995 (Box 9)
  - Jefferson Street Church (Box 9)
  - 40th Anniversary Letters from Former Pastors and Their Wives 1934 (Box 9)
  - History (Box 9)
  - Local Expense Fund-Receipts and Expenditures 1939-1940 (Box 9)
  - Meetings of the Leaders 1891-1908 (Box 9)
  - Members, Baptisms, and Probationers Record Book circa 1900-1928 (Box 10)
  - Memorial Garden 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1887-1996 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings About the Church and Its Activities 1955-1995 (Box 10)
  - Notes on the History of the Church (Box 10)
  - P.I.E. (Persons Involved in Evangelism) Program 1991-1994 (Box 10)
  - Parsonage Litigation 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Princess Anne Circle Minute Books 1953-1963 (Box 10)
  - Purchase of Organ 1957 (Box 10)
  - Receipts and Expenditures Book 1879-1893 (Box 10)
  - Reminiscences by Long-Time Church Members 1987 (Box 10)
  - Reynolds, Betty-Presentations on the History of the Church 1987-1992 (Box 10)
  - Songs by Sandee Overmars (Box 10)
  - Stained Glass Windows
    - Correspondence and Windows 1969-1975, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Michigan Stained Glass Census 1992-1997 (Box 10)
  - Summer Non-Giver Letters 1984-1989 (Box 10)
  - UNISON-A Strategy for Interfaith Collaboration in Washtenaw County 1994 (Box 10)
  - United Methodist Youth Fellowship (formerly Epworth League)
    - General 1956-1989 (Box 10)
    - Minutes 1900-1917 (Box 10)
  - Ushers 1960-1981 (Box 10)
  - Vacation Church School 1959-1983 (Box 10)
  - West, Nellie-Certificates and Awards 1940-1954 (Box 10)
  - YAGO Group 1960 (Box 10)
  - Youth Activities 1965-1968 (Box 10)
- Publications File
  The Publications File (2.5 feet) contains church publications, including newsletters (starting 1957), Sunday bulletins (starting 1949 -- incomplete), annual church directories (starting 1946). Also included are miscellaneous other publications, including a 1997 history of the church and a history of the Central Conference of the German Methodist Church.
  - Advent Booklets 1986-1987 (Box 10)
  - Hymnals circa 1915-1920 (Box 10)
    (with ads for local businesses owned by German-Americans)
  - History of the Central Conference of the German Methodist Church (Box 10)
  - History of the West Side United Methodist Church by Nancy Snyder 1997 (Box 10)
  - Newsletters
    - The Ecology of the Spirit
      - 1972-1973 (Box 11)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 11)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 11)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 11)
      - 1980 (Box 11)
      - 1981 (Box 11)
      - 1982 (Box 11)
      - 1983 (Box 11)
      - 1984 (Box 11)
    - News Sheet, 1957-1958 (Box 11)
    - The Open Door
      - 1959-1964 (Box 11)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 11)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 11)
      - 1969-1972 (Box 11)
    - Parish News, December 1933 (Box 11)
    - The Spirit
      - 1985 (Box 11)
      - 1986 (Box 11)
      - 1987 (Box 11)
      - 1988 (Box 11)
      - 1989 (Box 11)
      - 1990 (Box 11)
      - 1991 (Box 11)
      - 1992 (Box 11)
      - 1993 (Box 11)
      - 1994 (Box 11)
      - 1995 (Box 11)
      - 1996 (Box 11)
      - 1997 (Box 11)
  - Sunday Bulletins
    - 1949 1951 (Box 12)
    - 1954 (Box 12)
    - 1955 (Box 12)
    - 1956 (Box 12)
    - 1957 (Box 12)
    - 1958 (Box 12)
    - 1959 (Box 12)
    - 1963-1965 1971 (Box 12)
    - 1983 (Box 12)
    - 1984 (Box 12)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 12)
    - 1988 (Box 12)
    - 1989 (Box 12)
    - 1990 (Box 12)
    - 1991 (Box 12)
    - 1992 (Box 12)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 12)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 12)
  - Weiss, Edwin-Methodist Hymnal with Annotations and Notes (Box 12)
  - Weiss, Edwin-Sermon Titled "Memories," 1972 (Box 12)
  - Yearbooks (Directories)
    - 1946-1948 (Box 12)
    - 1949-1953 (Box 12)
    - 1953-1955 (Box 12)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 12)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 12)
    - 1959-1961 (Box 12)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 12)
    - 1963-1967 (Box 13)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 13)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 13)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 13)
    - 1976-1978 (Box 13)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 13)
    - 1981-1984 (Box 13)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 13)
    - 1987-1990 (Box 13)
    - 1991-1995 (Box 13)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 13)
  - Yearbooks-Pictorial 1971-2000 (Box 13)
- Photographs and Postcard File
  The Photographs and Postcard File (1.3 feet) contains photographs of church buildings and church activities. Although the bulk of them date from period since the move to Seventh Street, a few pictures of the original building at Liberty and Division are included along with a significant number from the years on Jefferson Street. Also included is a fairly complete set of photographs of former ministers dating back to the founding of the church. Topics include church services; social activities; Sunday School; youth activities; ceremonies honoring ministers and staff; and construction and consecration of the Seventh Street building, the education building, and the connecting wing.
  - Album on Church Activities 1983-1985, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Anniversaries-100th 1947 (Box 13)
  - Anniversaries-110th 1957 (Box 13)
  - Anniversaries-140th 1987 (Box 13)
  - Anniversaries-150th 1997, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Banks, Rev. Milton-With Hand-Made Cross in Front of Church (Box 13)
  - Baptisms (Box 13)
  - Bell Choir (Box 13)
  - Berkompas, Rev. Elwood-(30 years in ministry) and Rev. Cardwell Prout (10 years at West Side) (Box 13)
  - Berkompas, Rev. Elwood-Retirement Ceremony 1995 (Box 13)
  - Berkompas, Rev. Elwood-Retirement Dinner 1995 (Box 13)
  - Bishop Ott's Visit 1994 (Box 13)